This summer I was back in Ohio for a family wedding,
هذا الصيف، عدت إلى أوهايو لحضور حفل زفاف عائلي.
there was a meet and greet with Anna and Elsa from "Frozen."
أقيم حفل استقبال وترحيب مع آنا واليسا من فلم "فروزن".
Not the Anna and Elsa from "Frozen,"
بالتأكيد ليس آنا وإلسا من الفلم.
as this was not a Disney-sanctioned event.
لأنه ليس حدثا ترعاه ديزني.
These two entrepreneurs had a business of running princess parties.
هاتان المتعهدتان تديران عملاً هو إقامة حفلات الأميرة.
Your kid is turning five?
طفلك سيلغ الخامسة؟
They'll come sing some songs, sprinkle some fairy dust, it's great.
ستأتيان لغناء بعض الأغاني، و تنثرن غبار الحوريات، إنه لأمر رائع.
And they were not about to miss out on the opportunity
ولن تفوتا الفرصة
that was the phenomenon and that was "Frozen."
والتي هي الفلم الظاهرة "فروزن".
So they get hired by a local toy store,
تم تعيينهما من قبل متجر ألعاب محلي.
kids come in on a Saturday morning,
يحضر الأطفال صباح السبت،
buy some Disney swag, get their picture taken with the princesses,
يشترون بعضاً من منتجات ديزني، و يلتقطون صورا مع الأميرات،
call it a day.
وبذلك ينتهي اليوم.
It's like Santa Claus without the seasonal restrictions.
شبيه بتقليد ببابا نويل باستثناء القيود الموسمية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And my three-and-a-half-year-old niece Samantha was in the thick of it.
ابنة أختي سامانثا ذات الثلاث سنوات ونصف كانت في بؤرة الاهتمام بذلك.
She could care less that these two women were signing posters and coloring books
لم تكن لتهتم بأن هاتين السيدتين تقومان بتوقيع الملصقات ودفاترالتلوين،
as Snow Queen and Princess Ana with one N to avoid copyright lawsuits.
كأميرة الثلج وآنا بحرف N واحد لتجنب انتهاك حقوق النشر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
According to my niece and the 200-plus kids in the parking lot that day,
برأي ابنة اختي وأكثر من 200 طفل آخرين في موقف السيارات ذلك اليوم،
this was the Anna and Elsa from "Frozen."
هاتان السيدتان هما آنا وإلسا من الفلم "فروزن".
It is a blazing hot Saturday morning in August in Ohio.
لقد كان صباح يوم سبت بأشعة شمس حارقة في شهر أغسطس في مدينة أوهايو،
We get there at 10 o'clock, the scheduled start time,
وصلنا إلى هناك في العاشرة صباحاً، موعد البدء المقرر،
and we are handed number 59.
وتم إعطائنا دور برقم 59.
By 11 o'clock they had called numbers 21 through 25;
بحلول الساعة 11 تمت مناداة الأرقام بين 21 و 25؛
this was going to be a while,
إذاً سننتظر لفترة طويلة.
and there is no amount of free face painting or temporary tattoos
ولا يوجد ما يكفي من الرسم على الوجوه أو الوشم المؤقت المجانيين،
that could prevent the meltdowns that were occurring outside of the store.
لمنع حدوث الانهيار خارج المتجر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So, by 12:30 we get called:
بحلول الساعة 12:30 جاء دورنا:
"56 to 63, please."
"ليتفضل حاملوا الأرقام بين 56 و 63 من فضلهم."
And as we walk in, it is a scene I can only describe you
ومع دخولنا، يمكن وصف المكان بطريقة وحيدة،
as saying it looked like Norway threw up.
وذلك بالقول أن النرويج قد تقيأت في المتجر.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
There were cardboard cut-out snowflakes covering the floor,
كان هناك قطع من الورق المقوى المقصوصة على شكل ندف من الثلج تغطي الأرضية.
glitter on every flat surface, and icicles all over the walls.
زينة على الأرضية، كتل ثلجية على الجدران.
And as we stood in line
وعندما كنا ننتظر في الدور
in an attempt to give my niece a better vantage point
في محاولة لتوفير رؤية أفضل لبنت أختي
than the backside of the mother of number 58,
من خلفية والدة الرقم 58،
I put her up on my shoulders,
وضعتها على كتفي،
and she was instantly riveted by the sight of the princesses.
فسحرت بمنظر الأميرتين في الحال.
And as we moved forward, her excitement only grew,
وازدادت حماستها كلما اقترب دورنا
and as we finally got to the front of the line,
وعندما وصلنا إلى مقدمة الدور،
and number 58 unfurled her poster to be signed by the princesses,
ورقم 58 فردت ملصقها ليتم توقيعه من قبل الأميرتين،
I could literally feel the excitement running through her body.
أصبح بإمكاني الإحساس بحماسة ابنة أختي تجري في جسدها،
And let's be honest, at that point, I was pretty excited too.
ولنكون صريحين، في تلك اللحظة، أنا أيضاً كنت متحمسةً.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
I mean, the Scandinavian decadence was mesmerizing.
البذخ الإسكندنافي كان يسيل اللعاب.
So we get to the front of the line,
إذاً وصلنا إلى مقدمة الدور،
and the haggard clerk turns to my niece and says,
والموظفة المتعبة تنظر إلى ابنة أختي وتقول:
"Hi, honey. You're next!
"مرحباً عزيزتي، أنت التالية"
Do you want to get down, or you're going to stay
هل تريدين النزول أم تودين البقاء،
on your dad's shoulders for the picture?'
على كتف والدك من أجل الصورة؟
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And I was, for a lack of a better word, frozen.
وشعرت، بسبب عدم وجود كلمة أفضل، بأني متجمدة
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
It's amazing that in an unexpected instant we are faced with the question,
إنه من المذهل كيف أنه في اللحظات غير المتوقعة يواجهنا السؤال،
who am I?
من أنا؟
Am I an aunt? Or am I an advocate?
هل أنا خالة؟ أم محامية؟
Millions of people have seen my video about how to have a hard conversation,
ملايين الأشخاص شاهدو فيلمي عن كيفية مواجهة محادثة صعبة،
and there one was, right in front of me.
والآن تواجهني واحدة.
At the same time,
في نفس الوقت،
there's nothing more important to me than the kids in my life,
لايوجد عندي ما هو أهم من من الأطفال في حياتي
so I found myself in a situation that we so often find ourselves in,
لذا وجدت نفسي في موقف طالما نواجهه،
torn between two things, two impossible choices.
منقسمة بين أمرين، اختيارين مستحيلين.
Would I be an advocate?
هل سأجابه الأمر كمحامية؟
Would I take my niece off my shoulders and turn to the clerk and explain to her
هل أنزل ابنة أختي من على كتفي واستدير للموظفة وأشرح لها
that I was in fact her aunt, not her father,
أنني في الحقيقة خالتها لست والدها،
and that she should be more careful
وأنها يجب أن تتوخى الحذر أكثر،
and not to jump to gender conclusions based on haircuts and shoulder rides --
وأن لا تتأخذ قرارات حول الجنس اعتمادا على قصات الشعر وحمل الأطفال على الأكتاف.
(Laughter) --
(ضحك)
and while doing that,
وأثناء القيام بذلك،
miss out on what was, to this point, the greatest moment of my niece's life.
تضييع ماكان حتى هذه اللحظة أعظم لحظات حياة ابنة أختي.
Or would I be an aunt?
أو التزم بكوني خالة؟
Would I brush off that comment, take a million pictures,
هل اترك هذا التعليق يمضي، التقط مليون صورة،
and not be distracted for an instant from the pure joy of that moment,
ولا أفقد انتباهي ولو للحظة عن الفرحة النقية التي تعم اللحظة،
and by doing that,
ومن خلال القيام بذلك،
walk out with the shame that comes up for not standing up for myself,
الخروج بالعار الذي يرافق عدم دفاعي عن نفسي،
especially in front of my niece.
وخاصةً أمام ابنة أختي.
Who was I?
من كنت ؟!
Which one was more important? Which role was more worth it?
أيهما أهم؟ أي أدور كان يستحق أكثر؟
Was I an aunt? Or was I an advocate?
هل كنت خالة؟ أم كنت محامية؟
And I had a split second to decide.
وجلًُ ما كلن لدي جزء من ثانية لكي أقرر.
We are taught right now
يتم تعليمنا،
that we are living in a world of constant and increasing polarity.
أننا نعيش في عالم ذو تناقض ثابت ومتزايد.
It's so black and white, so us and them, so right and wrong.
إنه عالم إما أبيض أو أسود، إما نحن أو هم، إما صحيح أو خاطئ.
There is no middle, there is no gray, just polarity.
لايوجد حل وسط، لايوجد منطقة رمادية، فقط تناقض.
Polarity is a state in which two ideas or opinions
التناقض: هو حالة يكون فيها فكرتين أو رأيين،
are completely opposite from each other;
متعاكسان تماماً.
a diametrical opposition.
تعاكس تام.
Which side are you on?
بصف من أنت؟
Are you unequivocally and without question antiwar, pro-choice, anti-death penalty,
هل أنت ضد الحرب، مناصر للإجهاض، ضد عقوبة الإعدام بالمطلق وبشكل لا لبس فيه،
pro-gun regulation, proponent of open borders and pro-union?
مع قوانين الحد من انتشار السلاح، مؤيد لفتح الحدود والاتحادية.
Or, are you absolutely and uncompromisingly
أو، هل أنت بالمطلق ودون هوادة
pro-war, pro-life, pro-death penalty,
مع الحرب، ضد الإجهاض، مع عقوبة الإعدام،
a believer that the Second Amendment is absolute,
مؤمن بشكل مطلق بالبند الثاني. (الخاص بحمل السلاح)
anti-immigrant and pro-business?
ضد الهجرة ومؤيد لقطاع العمل.
It's all or none, you're with us or against us.
كل شيء أو لاشيء أنت معنا أو ضدنا.
That is polarity.
هذا هو التناقض.
The problem with polarity and absolutes is that
مشكلة التناقض والمطلقات أنها:
it eliminates the individuality of our human experience
تلغي الفردية من تجربتنا الإنسانية،
and that makes it contradictory to our human nature.
وتجعلها مناقضة لطبيعتنا البشرية.
But if we are pulled in these two directions,
ولكن إذا تم سحبنا في هذين الاتجاهين،
but it's not really where we exist --
ولكن ليس مكان وجودنا تماماً...
polarity is not our actual reality --
التناقض ليس واقعنا الفعلي...
where do we go from there?
إلى أين نذهب من هناك؟
What's at the other end of that spectrum?
ماذا يوجد في الطرف الآخر من الطيف؟
I don't think it's an unattainable, harmonious utopia,
لاأظن انها مدينة فاضلة متناغمة لايمكن الوصول إليها،
I think the opposite of polarity is duality.
أعتقد أن عكس التناقض الازدواجية.
Duality is a state of having two parts,
الازدواجية: هي حالة امتلاك جزئين،
but not in diametrical opposition,
ولكن ليس في حالة تناقض تام،
in simultaneous existence.
بل بوجود متزامن.
Don't think it's possible?
ألاتعتقد أنه ممكن؟
Here are the people I know:
هؤلاء الأشخاص الذين أعرفهم:
I know Catholics who are pro-choice, and feminists who wear hijabs,
أعرف كاثوليكيين مع الإجهاض، ومناصرين للمرأة يلبسون الحجاب،
and veterans who are antiwar,
ومقاتلين قدامى ضد الحرب،
and NRA members who think I should be able to get married.
وعضو في NRA يعتقد أنه يجب أن يكون بإمكاني الزواج.
Those are the people I know, those are my friends and family,
هؤلاء هم الأشخاص الذين أعرفهم، هؤلاء أصدقائي وعائلتي،
that is the majority of our society, that is you, that is me.
هؤلاء هم غالبية مجتمعنا، إنه أنا وأنت.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Duality is the ability to hold both things.
الازدواجية: هي القدرة على التمسك بكلا الأمرين
But the question is: Can we own our duality?
ولكن السؤال هو: هل يمكننا امتلاك ازدواجيتنا؟
Can we have the courage to hold both things?
هل نمتلك الشجاعة للتمسك بكلا الأمرين؟
I work at a restaurant in town,
أعمل في مطعم في البلدة،
I became really good friends with the busser.
أصبحت صديقة جيدة مع منظفة الطاولات.
I was a server and we had a great relationship,
كنت نادلة، وكان بيننا صداقة كبيرة،
we had a really great time together.
أمضينا وقتاً ممتعاً سوية.
Her Spanish was great
لغتها الإسبانية كانت ممتازة،
because she was from Mexico.
لأنها مكسيكية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
That line actually went the other way.
لقد فهم هذا السطر بطريقة مخالفة لما توقعت.
Her English was limited, but significantly better than my Spanish.
لغتها الإنكليزية كانت محدودة، ولكن أفضل من لغتي الإسبانية بمراحل.
But we were united by our similarities,
ولكن وحدتنا تشابهاتنا.
not separated by our differences.
ولم تفرقنا اختلافاتنا.
And we were close, even though we came from very different worlds.
وكنا مقربتين بالرغم من اننا أتينا من عالمين مختلفين كثيراً.
She was from Mexico,
كانت مكسيكية،
she left her family behind so she could come here
تركت عائلتها لكي نسنطيع أن تأتي إلى هنا،
and afford them a better life back home.
وتأمن لهم ظروف معيشية أفضل في بلدهم.
She was a devout conservative Catholic,
كانت كاثوليكية محافظة متفانية،
a believer in traditional family values,
مؤمنة بقيم العائلة التقليدية،
stereotypical roles of men and women,
الأدوار المفترضة من الرجال والنساء،
and I was, well, me.
وأنا كنت، حسنا، أنا.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But the things that bonded us were when she asked about my girlfriend,
ولكن الأشياء التي جمعتنا كانت عندما تسألني عن صديقتي الحميمة،
or she shared pictures that she had from her family back home.
أو عندما شاركتني بصور لعائلتها من وطنهم.
Those were the things that brought us together.
هذه هي الأشياء التي قربتنا من بعضنا.
So one day, we were in the back,
في يوم من الأيام، كنا في الخلف
scarfing down food as quickly as we could, gathered around a small table,
نأكل بأقصى سرعة ممكنة، مجتمعين حول طاولة صغيرة،
during a very rare lull,
خلال هدوء مؤقت نادر الحدوث،
and a new guy from the kitchen came over --
والشخص الجديد من المطبخ أتى..
who happened to be her cousin --
كان ابن عمها..
and sat down with all the bravado and machismo
وجلس معنا متحلياً بكل التبجح والرجولة
that his 20-year-old body could hold.
الذي بإمكان جسده ذو العشرين عاماً حمله.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And he said to her, [in Spanish] "Does Ash have a boyfriend?"
وقال لها (بالإسبانية): "هل لدى آش صديق حميم"
And she said, [in Spanish] "No, she has a girlfriend."
فقالت (بالإسبانية): "لا، لديها صديقة حميمة"
And he said, [in Spanish] "A girlfriend?!?"
فقال (بالإسبانية): "صديقة حميمة؟"
And she set down her fork, and locked eyes with him,
فوضعت شوكتها، ونظرت في عينيه،
and said, [in Spanish] "Yes, a girlfriend. That is all."
وقالت (بالإسبانية): "نعم، صديقة حميمة. هذا كل شيء"
And his smug smile quickly dropped to one of maternal respect,
وابتسامته الأنيقة اختفت بسرعة ابتسامة احترام الأمهات.
grabbed his plate, walked off, went back to work.
أخذ صحنه، ومشى بعيداً عائداً إلى العمل.
She never made eye contact with me.
لم تنظر إلي أبداً.
She left, did the same thing --
لقد غادرت، قامت بنفس الشيء..
it was a 10-second conversation, such a short interaction.
لقد كانت محادثة بطول ثواني، ياله من تبادل قصير.
And on paper, she had so much more in common with him:
على الورق، كان لديها الكثير مشترك معه:
language, culture, history, family, her community was her lifeline here,
اللغة، الثقافة، التاريخ، العائلة، مجتمعها كان حبل النجاة بالنسبة لها هنا.
but her moral compass trumped all of that.
ولكن بوصلتها الأخلاقية لفقت كل ذلك.
And a little bit later, they were joking around in the kitchen in Spanish,
وبعد فترة وجيزة، كانا يمزحان مع بعضهما في المطبخ،
that had nothing to do with me,
ولم يكن لي صلة بالموضوع،
and that is duality.
تلك هي الازدواجية.
She didn't have to choose some P.C. stance on gayness over her heritage.
لم يكن واجباً عليها اختيار موقف صحيح سياسياً بخصوص اللوطية على حساب تراثها.
She didn't have to choose her family over our friendship.
لم يكن واجباً عليها اختيار عائلتها على حساب صداقتنا.
It wasn't Jesus or Ash.
لم يكن الأمر اليسوع أو آش
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Her individual morality was so strongly rooted
أخلاقها الفردية كانت ذات جذور عميقة
that she had the courage to hold both things.
كفاية لكي تتمسك بكلا الأمرين.
Our moral integrity is our responsibility
نزاهتنا الأخلاقية هي مسؤوليتنا
and we must be prepared to defend it even when it's not convenient.
ويجب علينا ان نكون جاهزين للدفاع عنها حتى عندما لايكون الوضع مناسباً.
That's what it means to be an ally, and if you're going to be an ally,
هذا ما يعنيه كونك حليفاً، فإذا كنت ستصبح حليفاً،
you have to be an active ally:
يجب عليك أن تكون حليفاً نشطاً:
Ask questions, act when you hear something inappropriate,
اسأل الأسئلة، تصرف عندما تسمع شيئاً غير ملائم،
actually engage.
اشترك بفاعلية.
I had a family friend who for years used to call my girlfriend my lover.
كان لدي صديقة للعائلة، لسنوات اعتادت على مناداة صديقتي الحميمة عشيقتي.
Really? Lover?
حقاً؟ عشيقتي؟
So overly sexual,
لذا الأمر متعلق بممارسة الجنس فقط،
so '70s gay porn.
لذا أفلام السبعينيات الإباحية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But she was trying, and she asked.
ولكنها كانت تحاول، وسألت.
She could have called her my friend,
كان باستطاعتها مناداتها صديقتي،
or my "friend," or my "special friend" --
أو "صديقتي" أو "صديقتي الخاصة"..
(Laughter) --
(ضحك)
or even worse, just not asked at all.
أو حتى أسوأ، أن لاتسأل أبداً.
Believe me, we would rather have you ask.
صدقني، نفضل أن تسأل.
I would rather have her say lover, than say nothing at all.
أفضل أن تناديها عشيقة، على أن لاتقول أي شيء.
People often say to me, "Well, Ash, I don't care.
الناس غالباً ما تقول لي: "حسنا، آش، أنا لا أهتم
I don't see race or religion or sexuality.
لا أرى العرق أو الدين أو التفضيل الجنسي.
It doesn't matter to me. I don't see it."
إنها لاتهمني. لا أراها"
But I think the opposite of homophobia and racism and xenophobia is not love,
ولكن أظن أن عكس الخوف من اللوطية والعنصرية والخوف من الأجانب ليس الحب،
it's apathy.
إنه اللامبالاة.
If you don't see my gayness, then you don't see me.
إذا كنت لاترى لوطيتي، إذاً أنت لا تراني.
If it doesn't matter to you who I sleep with,
إذا كان لا يهمك من أشارك سريري معه،
then you cannot imagine what it feels like
إذاً لا يمكنك تخيل كيف أشعر
when I walk down the street late at night holding her hand,
عندما أمشي في الشارع في وقت متأخر من الليل ممسكةً يدها،
and approach a group of people and have to make the decision
عند الاقتراب من مجموعة من الناس واضطراري إلى اتخاذ القرار
if I should hang on to it or if I should I drop it
إذا ما كان يجب علي أن أظل ممسكة بيدها أو أن أتركها
when all I want to do is squeeze it tighter.
في حين أن كل ما أرغب به هو أن أضغطها أكثر.
And the small victory I feel
والنصر الصغير الذي أشعر به
when I make it by and don't have to let go.
عندما أستطيع أن أمر دون الحاجة لتركها.
And the incredible cowardice and disappointment I feel when I drop it.
والجبن والإحباط غير المعقول الذي أشعر به عند تركها.
If you do not see that struggle
إذا كنت لا ترى هذه المعاناة
that is unique to my human experience because I am gay, then you don't see me.
الفريدة في تجربتي الإنسانية لأنني لوطية، إذاً أنت لا تراني.
If you are going to be an ally, I need you to see me.
إذا كنت ستصبح حليفاً، أريد منك أن تراني.
As individuals, as allies, as humans,
كأفراد، كحلفاء، كبشر،
we need to be able to hold both things:
يجب علينا أن نتمكن من الإمساك بكلا الأمرين:
both the good and the bad,
الجيد والسيء،
the easy and the hard.
السهل والصعب.
You don't learn how to hold two things just from the fluff,
لا يمكنك تعلم الإمساك بكلا الأمرين من خلال الزغب (المواقف السهلة)
you learn it from the grit.
تتعلمه من الرمل (المواقف الصعبة)
And what if duality is just the first step?
وماذا إذا كانت الازدواجية هي الخطوة الأولى فقط؟
What if through compassion and empathy and human interaction
ماذا إذا كان من خلال الشفقة والتعاطف والتواصل البشري
we are able to learn to hold two things?
يمكننا تعلم الإمساك بكلا الأمرين؟
And if we can hold two things, we can hold four,
وإذا أمكننا الإمساك بكلا الأمرين يمكننا الإمساك بأربع
and if we can hold four, we can hold eight,
وإذا تمكنا من الإمساك بأربع يمكننا الإمساك بثمانية،
and if we can hold eight, we can hold hundreds.
وإذا تمكنا من الإمساك بثمانية يمكننا الإمساك بالمئات.
We are complex individuals,
إننا أفراد معقدون،
swirls of contradiction.
دوامات من المتناقضات.
You are all holding so many things right now.
كل منكم يمسك بكثير من الأشياء الآن.
What can you do to hold just a few more?
مالذي بإمكانك القيام به لكي تمسك بأكثر؟
So, back to Toledo, Ohio.
لذا، بالعودة إلى توليدو في أوهايو.
I'm at the front of the line,
أنا عند مقدمة الدور،
niece on my shoulders, the frazzled clerk calls me Dad.
ابنة أختي على كتفي، الموظفة المنهكة تناديني بالأب.
Have you ever been mistaken for the wrong gender?
هل تم خلطك مع الجنس الخطأ؟
Not even that.
ولا حتى ذلك.
Have you ever been called something you are not?
هل تم مناداتك بشيء أنت لست عليه؟
Here's what it feels like for me:
سأخبرك بشعوري تجاه ذلك:
I am instantly an internal storm of contrasting emotions.
شعرت فوراً بعاصفة داخلية من المشاعر المتضادة.
I break out into a sweat that is a combination of rage and humiliation,
أتصبب عرقاً ناتجاً عن الغضب والشعور بالإذلال،
I feel like the entire store is staring at me,
أشعر بأن كل المتجر يحدق بي،
and I simultaneously feel invisible.
وفي نفس الوقت أشعر بأني خفية.
I want to explode in a tirade of fury,
أريد ان انفجر بخطبة غاضبة طويلة،
and I want to crawl under a rock.
وأريد ان أختبأ تحت صخرة.
And top all of that off with the frustration that I'm wearing
وأضف إلى كل ذلك الإحباط الناتج عن ارتدائي
an out-of-character tight-fitting purple t-shirt,
لقميص نهدي ضيق،
so this whole store can see my boobs,
لذا، كل المتجر يستطيع رؤية صدري،
to make sure this exact same thing doesn't happen.
للتأكد أن مثل هكذا موقف لن يحدث.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But, despite my best efforts to be seen as the gender I am,
لكن، بالرغم من بذل قصارى جهدي لأظهر كامرأة،
it still happens.
مازال الخلط يحدث.
And I hope with every ounce of my body that no one heard --
وآمل بكل ذرة من جسدي أن أحداً لم يسمع..
not my sister, not my girlfriend, and certainly not my niece.
لا أختي ولا صديقتي الحميمة، وبالتأكيد ليس ابنة أختي.
I am accustomed to this familiar hurt,
أنا معتادة على هكذا إيذاء مألوف،
but I will do whatever I need to do to protect the people I love from it.
ولكن سأقوم بأي شيء يمكنني القيام به لكي أحمي الأشخاص الذين أحبهم منه.
But then I take my niece off my shoulders,
لكن عندها انزل ابنة اختي من على أكتافي،
and she runs to Elsa and Anna --
فتركض إلى إلسا و آنا...
the thing she's been waiting so long for --
الشيء الذي انتظرته طويلاً...
and all that stuff goes away.
كل تلك الأشياء تتلاشى.
All that matters is the smile on her face.
كل ما يهم هو ابتسامتها.
And as the 30 seconds we waited two and a half hours for comes to a close
وعند اقتراب انتهاء الثلاثين ثانية التي انتظرناها ساعتين ونصف
we gather up our things, and I lock eyes with the clerk again;
جمعنا أغراضنا، ونظرت في عيني الموظفة مرة أخرى؛
and she gives me an apologetic smile and mouths,
وتبتسم ابتسامة اعتذار وتحرك شفتيها،
"I am so sorry!"
بكلمة "أنا آسفة!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And her humanity, her willingness to admit her mistake disarms me immediately,
إنسانيتها، رغبتها بالاعتراف بخطأها يهدأني فوراً،
then I give her a: "It's okay, it happens. But thanks."
فأقول لها: "لابأس، هذا يحدث، ولكن شكراً."
And I realize in that moment
وأدرك في تلك اللحظة
that I don't have to be
أنه لا يجب علي
either an aunt or an advocate, I can be both.
أن أكون خالة أو محامية، يمكنني أن أكون كلاهما.
I can live in duality, and I can hold two things.
أستطيع العيش بازدواجية وأستطيع الإمساك بأمرين،
I can hold so many more things.
أستطيع أن أمسك أشياء أكثر بكثير.
As my girlfriend and my niece hold hands and skip out the front of the door,
وبينما صديقتي الحميمة وابنة أختي تمسكان يدي بعضهما وتخرجان من الباب،
I turn to my sister and say, "Was it worth it?"
أستدير إلى أختي وأقول: "هل كان الأمر يستحق؟"
And she said, "Are you kidding me?
فتقول لي: "هل تمازحينني؟
Did you see the look on her face? This was the greatest day of her life!"
هل رأيتي النظرة على وجهها؟ لقد كان هذا أعظم أيام حياتها!"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"It was worth the two and a half hours in the heat,
"لقد كان يستحق الانتظار لساعتين ونصف في الحر،
it was worth the overpriced coloring book that we already had a copy of."
لكن كان يستحق دفتر التلوين الغالي الذي لدينا نسخة عنه."
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
"It was even worth you getting called Dad."
"لقد كان يستحق حتى أن تتم مناداتك بالأب."
And for the first time ever in my life, it actually was.
ولأول مرة على الإطلاق في حياتي، كان فعلياً يستحق.
Thank you, Boulder. Have a good night.
شكراً لكم. أتمنى لكم ليلة سعيدة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)